[Music]
after my video on dates blew my mind
showing that even just a few dates can
significantly reduceed the duration of
Labor during childbirth and improve the
progression of Labor when I saw that
there were randomized controlled trials
showing that penut balls could decrease
the length of Labor I didn't bat ey but
no this is the peanut ball they were
talking about uh but there are some
surprising benefits attributed to nuts
and randomized control trials like how
about a study on the effects of almond
consumption on wrinkles where' they even
come up with the idea well population
Studies have found that healthy diets
are associated with less facial wrinkles
like a a meat and junk predominant
eating pattern was associated with more
wrinkles whereas a fruit predominant
pattern was associated with fewer
wrinkles in terms of single Foods yellow
vegetables and soy appeared protective
but wine may make things worse they're
thinking is that it might be the
antioxidants in healthy foods decreasing
the oxidative stress load or the
anti-inflammatory benefits or protection
from sun damage or improved collagen
production or better DNA repair I've got
videos on most of those topics the
bottom line is that eating healthier May
reduce wrinkling which could actually
save lives if people started eating
healthier to maintain a more youthful
appearance and get all the chronic
disease benefits as a happy side effect
other studies found the same thing
supporting recommendations for more
healthy foods like fruits vegetables and
nuts here's another study that landed on
yellow vegetables and greens as well in
this study a high intake of vegetables
beans and olive oil appear to be
protective against spots of precancerous
sun damage whereas a high intake of meat
and dairy may make things worse prunes
apples and tea seem particularly good
but this is a cross-sectional study
meaning just a snapshot in time maybe
people who eat more meat are out
barbecuing in the Sun or or people who
eat more prunes just use more sunblock I
mean you can't know for sure if Foods
actually affect wrinkling until you put
them to the test but we had no such
studies
until
now why study almonds because it was
paid for by the Almond Board of course
the researchers didn't know who was in
the nut group though and who was in the
control group when they were looking at
the results the nut group were given 2
ounces of nuts a day like two Palm FS of
nuts and the control group was instead
given nut-free snacks to eat instead
like nut-free granola bars or pretzels
before and after they got highres facial
photographs to quantify facial wrinkle
depth and severity using a
computer-based photographic analysis and
boom the Almond group had significant L
decreased wrinkle severity compared with
the control group by the end of the
16-week study the paper concludes our
study demonstrates that daily almond
consumption May reduce wrinkle
severity now they used a relatively
large dose of 2 ounces a day whereas you
can get cardioprotective benefits of
nuts from even less than a half an ounce
so who knows maybe they could have
gotten away with using less here's the
lowd do nut study they referenced
showing a significant drop in LDL
cholesterol within 6 weeks eating just a
few almonds a day 10 grams is just like
eight almonds a day that's the nice
thing about healthy foods they just have
good side effects so Global disease
prevention strategies might benefit from
emphasizing that a healthy diet is also
linked to less facial wrinkling and
maybe vanity will help us prevent a few
heart attacks in the bargain
[Music]